感傷に浸(ひた)っているところ悪いけれど
I'm sorry I interrupted a rather
emotional moment, Devil Brother.
鬼いちゃん
Devil Brother
いったい何があったのさ?
What's going on?
あの蝸牛の子のことで思いつめるのは
仕方ないとは思うけれど
I wouldn't fault you for being depressed over what happened to the snail girl,
だからと言ってその辺の女と無理心中とか
やめてあげて欲しいな
but I'd rather you refrain from
murder-suicide with this girl here.
誤解もはなはだしいわ
That's a serious misunderstanding.
Don't call her "the girl there."
Kanbaru is my cute junior.
こいつが神原駿河だよ
Also, her name is Kanbaru Suruga.
ああ そうなんだ
Oh, I see.
この子が 臥煙(がえん)さんの姪っ子か
So this is Gaen's niece.
旧姓臥煙駿河
Her name used to be Gaen Suruga.
臥煙さんのお姉さんが籍を入れてからは神原駿河
It was changed to Kanbaru Suruga when Gaen's sister got married.
斧乃木ちゃんこそ どうしてここに?
And why are you here, Ononoki?
なに たまたまだ
Just passing by.
鬼いちゃんを助けるつもりなんてなかった
I didn't want to rescue you.
僕は僕の仕事をしていただけだ
I was busy with my work.
その仕事先で 鬼いちゃんが知らない女と
無理心中をしようとしていたので
Then I found you about to engage in a
murder-suicide with a girl I didn't know,
ひゃっほうこれは邪魔するしかないぜと思っただけだ
and thought, "Right-o, time to bust the party."
とにかく ありがとう 斧乃木ちゃん
Anyway, thank you, Ononoki.
きみには色々借りっぱなしだけど
いつか絶対に この恩は返すから
I'm in your debt for a lot of things, but I promise I'll repay you.
恩返しというのであれば
本来ならば巨万の富を積んで欲しいところだけれど
Normally I'd advise you to amass a
gargantuan fortune to repay this debt,
今回は僕の質問に答えてくれれば
それでいいにしてあげるよ
but for the time being, I'll settle for seeing my questions answered.
いったい何があったのさ?
What's going on?
End Story
Shinobu Mail
Shinobu Mail Part Two
End Story
鎧武者?
An armored warrior?
バラバラになっても自動的に組み上がる
You smashed it to pieces,
エナジードレインのスキルを持つ鎧武者?
and then it reassembled itself and used an energy drain?
Yeah.
ただし僕は 斧乃木ちゃんにすべてを告げてはいなかった
However, I did not tell Ononoki everything.
僕の心の中で まだ整理がついていない事柄を
斧乃木ちゃんにパスすることが どうしても躊躇(ためら)われた
I hesitated to relay to her what I myself had not yet fully adjusted to.
鎧武者の捨て台詞
The final words of the warrior.
2000 Liter Fire-Fighting Foam Tank
ありえない横文字
Those unlikely occidental words.
キスショット
Kiss-Shot.
Kiss-Shot
僕ですらもう呼ばないその名を 呼んだ
He called her by the name even I do not use.
そして妖刀"心渡"...
And he spoke of the demon sword Heart Span.
斧乃木ちゃん 心当たりはないのかい?
Do you have an idea, Ononoki?
その鎧武者は きみが今任されているという仕事と
何か関わりがあるのかい?
Do you think the armor is related to the work you were given?
Yes.
そうだね
うん そう
Yes, you're right.
確かにそれは その通り
僕の職掌の範囲内ではあるけれど
It does fall within the scope of my duties,
but when I listen to you,
しかし話を聞いていると それは僕がフィールドワークの対象としていた現象とは
ほとんど別物と言っていい
it seems an almost completely different being than the one I was dealing with.
なんだか 僕が探っていたときよりも
数段凶暴化している風だ
It seems to have become magnitudes
more violent since I was looking into it.
数日の間になにがあったんだろう?
What could have happened in these past few days?
そもそも僕が追っていた段階では
鎧武者でさえなかったし
It wasn't even a suit of armor when I was chasing it.
なあ 斧乃木ちゃん
Hey, Ononoki.
なんだい 鬼いちゃん
What is it?
降ろさせてもらっていいかな 今回
Can you let me off here?
ああ いや 違う 僕はいいんだよ
Actually, I'm fine.
僕は構わないんだけど
I'll stick it out.
神原...
But Kanbaru...
神原はもう帰してやってもいいだろ?
We can let her go home, right?
Uh, what?
何それ?
Are you saying you want to reject your promise to Gaen?
それはつまり 鬼いちゃん
臥煙さんとの約束を 反故(ほご)にするってこと?
Reject?
反故に...
You were able to utilize Gaen's knowledge on
the condition that you introduce this girl to her.
その子を臥煙さんに紹介するという約束で
あなたは臥煙さんの知恵を借りたんだろう?
It was absolutely necessary to save Hachikuji Mayoi,
それが八九寺真宵を救うためには絶対に必要なことであって
and realistically speaking you had no choice,
事実上あなたに選択肢はなかったとは言っても
それでも約束は約束だ
but a promise is a promise.
You show guts, Devil Brother.
いい度胸してるじゃないか 鬼いちゃん
惚れちゃいそうだよ
臥煙さんとの約束を破ろうだなんて
I find it slightly attractive that you're trying to break your promise to her.
約束を破るつもりは ないよ
It's not about breaking my promise...
いい胸筋をしているじゃないか
Your pectoral muscles are nice.
僕の胸筋について触れるな
Don't touch upon that subject.
触りたいなあ
I want to touch them.
筋肉に並々ならぬ興味を示すな
You show an unhealthy interest in my muscles.
僕は死体だからね
I'm a corpse.
肉に興味を示すのは本能みたいなものだ
Showing interest in living flesh is normal.
理由は?
What's your reason?
臥煙さんとの約束を破ろうという理由だよ
Why are you breaking your promise to Gaen?
神原を紹介すること自体は
やぶさかじゃあないよ 今だって
It's not that I feel reluctant to introduce her to Gaen.
でも 約束はそれだけじゃなかっただろう?
But wasn't there more to the promise?
あの人は 神原にそちら側の仕事を手伝わそうとしていた
Isn't she going to give her your sort of work?
臥煙さんは言っていた
Gaen said
神原の"左手" "左腕"が必要だと
that Kanbaru's left hand, her left arm, was important.
もちろん 臥煙さんから知恵と知識を
借りたのは僕であって
Of course, I was the one who used her knowledge,
神原は無関係なのだから
and Kanbaru had nothing to do with it,
あくまでも神原が同意したらという
前提条件あっての約束だったけれど
so the promise was made on the condition that she agrees to get involved.
それがそもそもの間違いだった
That was a mistake.
僕からの頼みごとを 神原が断るわけがないのは
重々わかっていたことじゃないか
I knew full well that she wouldn't refuse my request.
その結果 神原を考えられないような
危険に晒してしまった
And now I've exposed her to great danger.
完全に巻き込んでしまった
I dragged her into this mess.
先輩として
僕が断ってやらなければいけなかったのだ
I should have turned Gaen down as a responsible senior.
鬼いちゃんの気持ちはわかるよ
I can imagine how you feel.
だけど それは諦めたほうがいいな
You shouldn't think like that.
お勧めできない
I don't recommend it.
これは友達としての忠告だ
That's my warning as your friend.
I don't remember becoming friends with you.
きみと友達になった覚えがないが
I've been thinking of you as my friend for a long time.
僕はもうとっくに 鬼いちゃんのこと
友達だって思ってるぜ?
とっくに 後戻りは利かない状態なんだよ
We're long past the point of no return.
Why don't you understand that letting her go home doesn't protect her?
その子を家に帰したところで その子を守ることにはならないって
どうして思わないんだい?
え? どういう意味だ?
What do you mean?
怪異というのは 見るだけで障(さわ)る
遭うだけで呪う
Oddities affect you the minute you see them.
From the moment you meet them, you are cursed.
にもかかわらず その子はその鎧武者に
触れてしまったんだろう?
Didn't this girl touch the oddity?
そうか
I see.
もう神原駿河は
She is now
...she didn't just touch it, she punched it.
関わってしまったのだ
a part of this story.
Punched
鬼いちゃん 正座して
Kneel, Devil Brother.
Kneel. Now.
正座 早く
Do it.
とっとと
It behooves you.
疾(と)く疾く
It behooves you
ちょっと待ってね
Hold on.
すぐだから
It won't take long.
あの 斧乃木ちゃん
Um... Ononoki...
後戻りできるとか思ってんじゃねーぞ
Don't think we can go back to normal.
八九寺真宵の件と言い
Think of what happened with Hachikuji Mayoi.
鬼いちゃんには覚悟が足りない
You lack resolve, Devil Brother.
ねえ あなた いつだって人生はやり直せるとか
思っちゃってるんじゃない?
You think you can always have a fresh start in life, right?
何を始めるにも遅いなんてことはないって
思っちゃってるんじゃない?
You think it's never too late for something, right?
You think you can always rebound even if you fail, right?
失敗しても うっかりしても
取り返しはつくって思っちゃってるんじゃない?
That life always balances out to zero at the end?
人生は最後にはプラスマイナスゼロになる
だって?
Hah.
そりゃあ死んだらゼロになるのは当たり前だっつーの
Well, at the end of life there's zero left.
だから鬼いちゃん
その子のことを本当に思うのであれば
If you really treasure that girl, Devil Brother,
ここで家に帰すなんて無責任なことをせずに
you will not irresponsibly send her home,
むしろより一層
臥煙さんのところに連れて行くべきだよ
but take her to Gaen.
そして臥煙さんに保護してもらうべきだ
Have Gaen protect her.
臥煙さんに
Gaen?
Yes.
Protect
そう 約束を反故にせず
彼女を保護してもらうべきだ
Have her be protected, not the promise rejected.
Protect
Reject
確かに
She's right.
無責任と言うなら ここで神原を家に帰すほうが
よっぽど無責任かもしれない
Sending her home might be far more irresponsible.
I didn't seek the freedom to ruin my entire life
by breaking a promise I made to Gaen.
Even without that, I want to keep my promise.
I should keep it.
いや 正直になろう
No, let's be honest.
あんな危険な鎧武者に
神原を関わらせたくないのは当然だったが
Obviously I didn't want to involve her with such a dangerous armor,
ならば 僕が関わりたくないかと言えば
決してそんなことはないのだと
and if the question is whether or not I want to get caught up in it myself, the answer is also no.
むしろ 関わらずにはいられないのだと
However, I have no choice.
He entrusted me with a message.
A message to "my master."
I have to get involved if the armor really is what I think it is,
あの鎧武者の正体が
僕が思っている通りのものなのだとすれば
そんなことがあるはずはないと思ってはいても
ほんのわずかでも その可能性があるというのならば
no matter how unlikely it seems to me.
それを捨てられない
I can't ignore it.
それを知るまで 僕は家に帰れない
I can't go home until this is resolved.
You seem to have made a decision.
結論は出たようだね
やれやれ 友達って奴はまったく手間がかかるぜ
Golly, how bothersome friends can be.
I will now pursue the armored oddity you reportedly saw.
僕はこれから 鬼いちゃんが目撃したという
その鎧武者の怪異を追うことにする
Judging by the way it vanished, I don't think I'll find it.
その消えかたからすると
見つかるとは思えないけれど
無駄足を踏むのが僕の仕事だ
Going on fool's errands is my specialty.
鬼いちゃんの顔と無駄足を踏むのが僕の仕事だ
Being on fool's errands and stepping on your face.
言い直すな
Don't correct yourself.
仕事で僕の顔を踏むな
Don't make it your specialty.
だから鬼いちゃんはその姪っ子をお姫様抱っこして
臥煙さんと合流すればいいよ
Carry the niece to the meeting point you and Gaen decided on.
そして事情を説明するんだね
Explain your situation.
Your sentence makes it sound like she's my niece.
その言いかただと
神原が僕の姪みたいなんだが
We should all leave this area soon.
なんにしても 僕も鬼いちゃん達も
そろそろここを離れたほうがいい
Enjoying emotional moments in front
of burned-out ruins is fine too.
そろそろ消防や警察が
駆けつけてくる頃合いだ
It won't be long before police and fire fighters arrive.
退(の)き引(ひ)き加減の心得も
専門家に必須だぜ
A good specialist knows when to take flight.
気付いたか
Are you awake?
Araragi!
阿良々木先輩!
Are you okay?
無事だったか!
なんのつもりだね
What are you doing?
状況はよくわからないが
この機会を逃してはならないと私の本能が告げている
I have no idea what's going on, but my instincts are telling me not to pass up this chance.
すげーな お前の本能
Amazing instincts...
What are they telling her?
They're saying too much.
まだ歩けそうもない
I can't walk yet.
このまましばらくおぶってもらうことにした
You will have to carry me for a while.
I guess that's fine.
仕方ないなあ
もうちょっとだけだぞ
Just a little while.
肉体的にはともかく
精神的に疲弊(ひへい)しているのは確かなのだ
I'm exhausted mentally, to say nothing of physically.
なんだか 調子が悪い
I don't feel so well.
調子が?
Not well?
なんだか 北白蛇神社を思い出す
It makes me remember the Shrine of the Polar Snake.
Araragi, are we headed to the person you wanted to introduce me to?
阿良々木先輩 今は 私に紹介したいという
誰かのところに向かっている最中と言ったところか?
Uh, yeah...
ああ... うん そうなんだけど
それについては 神原
About that...
僕はお前に謝らなきゃならない
I have to apologize to you.
No need for apologies!
謝罪など不要だ
むしろ謝らないで欲しい
In fact, I don't even want you to.
阿良々木先輩に頭を下げさせてしまったなど
神原駿河の名折れだ
Seeing you bow in apology would sully my name.
And being carried by me does not?
だとすればおんぶさせていることのほうが
よっぽど神原駿河の名折れなのでは
Kanbaru
Suruga
See it getting all dirty?
折れてよれよれなのでは
いや 真面目な話
ここでお前を帰すほうが危険かもしれないんだ
Seriously though, it might be dangerous to send you home now.
Bargain Sale Ahead
せめて事情がわかるまでは
僕と行動を共にしてくれ
You should stay with me until we know what's going on.
私はいつでも阿良々木先輩からの頼みに
こう答えるまでだ
I will always respond to your requests like this...
召し上がれ♪
Dig in!
That's so annoying!
やかましいわ!
But also cute!
そして可愛いわ!
What did I request?
ただ 今どこに向かっているのかくらいは聞いておこうか
阿良々木先輩
I would be interested in knowing where we're going, though.
今は 言ってた合流地点に向かっている
To the meeting point, like you said.
えーっと お前は知ってるかな
You might know it.
浪白公園ってところなんだけど
It's called Rouhaku Park.
Rouhaku?
ろうはく?
なみしろかもしれない
Maybe it's read Namishiro.
戦場ヶ原の中学時代の縄張(なわば)りだったらしいだけれど
Senjougahara hung out there in middle school.
I might remember when I see it.
じゃあ見たら思い出すかもな
なんにしても了解だ 阿良々木先輩
Sounds good to me, Araragi!
今はその公園に向かっているんだな?
So, we're going to that park now, right?
そこに 私に会わせたい人とやらがいるんだな?
And I'm going to meet someone there?
まあ そうだ
Yeah...
でも だったら 阿良々木先輩
Well, Araragi,
方向 全然逆じゃないか?
aren't we going the completely wrong way then?
あれ? でも
What? But...
ちょっと引き返して ルートを修正するか
Let's turn back and go the right way.
ごめん神原
Sorry, Kanbaru.
なに 大過ない
It's no big deal.
すべて任す
You got it.
阿良々木先輩のいいようにしてくれ
Just do your thing.
Bargain Sale Ahead
Stop
One hour later
僕達はすっかり どこだかわからない場所にいた
We wound up somewhere we'd never seen before.
そう言えば阿良々木先輩
By the way, Araragi.
昔も道に迷ったことがあったとかなかったとか
ありそうでなかったとか 言っていなかったっけ?
Didn't you tell me once you that you lost track in the past?
ほら 八九寺ちゃんと
You know, when you were with Hachikuji?
No, wait.
いや 待て待て
迷い牛はもういないはずじゃないか
The Lost Cow is gone.
だが...
But...
おぬしも寄り道せず
まっすぐおうちに帰るがよかろう!
You will go home now without detours.
No, wait.
いや でもでも...
こんな嫌がらせというよりはただの意地悪みたいな仕掛けを
奴が打ってくるか?
Would he really do something like this,
truly malicious and not just a practical joke?
それに たとえこの"迷子"が 奴の仕業(しわざ)なのだとしても
その目的がわからない
Besides, even if it's his fault that we're lost, why would he do it?
僕と神原を 道に迷わせて 迷子にさせて
どうしようというんだ
What will he do now that we're lost?
神原 一旦降ろすぞ
Kanbaru, I'm letting go.
大根をか?
Is it because I'm fat?
お前をだ
No.
Actually, you're pretty thin.
Give up at
level one.
Calling
Gaen Izuko
やあ こよみん 待っていたよ
待ち遠しかったよ
Hello hello, Koyomin. I've been waiting a long time.
そろそろ電話をかけてくる頃だと思っていたんだ
I figured it was about time you called me.
で? 今はどうなってるんだい?
What's up right now?
臥煙おねーさんに教えておくれよ
Tell your friend Gaen.
えっとですね...
Um...
Crab
蟹かな?
Gaen Izuko
Crab? Snail? Monkey? Snake? Cat?
Crab
Snail
蝸牛かな?
Monkey
猿かな?
蛇かな?
Snake
Cat
猫かな?
あなたは何を知ってるんですか
What do you know?
私は何でも知っているよ
I know everything.
ご存知の通りね
You know that.
冗談だよ冗談
I'm just kidding!
何をマジになっているんだい こよみん
Why so serious, Koyomin?
五つも言えば どれかは当たるだろう
One of them is bound to be right if I mention all five.
大人の汚いやり口さ
It's a dirty trick adults use.
Gaen Izuko
Snail
Lost
Personally, my money is on the snail.
個人的には蝸牛だって予想するけどね
Cow
Snail
Lost
Cow
Snail
Lost
Cow
Snail
Lost
Cow
Snail
Lost
Cow
Snail
Snail—Lost Cow
当たってるじゃねえか
Well, that's correct.
なあに ヘルプの電話をかけられるような余裕があるのは
蝸牛だろうと思っただけさ
Come on, only the snail would give you enough time to call for help.
類推だよ
By analogy.
で どうなんだい?
So what is it?
その通りですよ ええ
You're correct.
今 神原と二人で
待ち合わせ場所の公園に向かっているところだったんですけれど
Kanbaru and I were headed to the park where we were going to meet you,
もうかれこれ一時間以上
but we've already wasted more than an hour.
Gaen Izuko
It turned out to be the most trivial one of what I imagined.
いったいどんな奴かと色々想像していたけれど
想定していた中じゃあ 一番小っちゃいなあ
こよみん
Koyomin.
早く合流してくださいな
Get over here ASAP.
詳しい話を 顔を突き合わせて聞きたくなってきたよ
I want to talk about the rest in person.
いえ だから
その合流ができないって話をしているんですよ
Like I was saying, we have trouble reaching you.
だから あなたからアドバイスをいただければと
I would like some kind of advice.
Children Passing
私がアドバイスするまでもないよ
I don't have to give you advice.
それはただのちょっかいだ
You're hardly even in trouble.
そのくらいの苦境は独力で乗り越えてもらえないと困る
I want you to deal with that yourself.
Thankfully, this isn't the first time that you've been lost.
幸い 道に迷うのはこれが初めてというわけじゃあないんだから
こよみん
Koyomin,
こはメメの主義に従って
一人で勝手に助かっておくれよ
let us heed Meme's philosophy and save ourselves alone.
No.
否
Gaen Izuko
一人じゃあないか
Not alone.
きみのそばには今
頼れる後輩がいるんだったね
You have someone with you to rely on.
だったらその子に頼ればいいだろう
Rely on her.
た 頼ればいいって
Rely on her?
あなた 神原を何だと思ってるんですか
Just who do you think Kanbaru is?
神原は
Kanbaru is—
Gaen Izuko
Kanbaru Suruga is my sister's daughter.
神原駿河は 私の姉の娘だよ
Gaen Izuko
眠らせておくには惜しい才能さ
Don't let her intellect go to waste.
She just hung up on me
電話は終わったか 阿良々木先輩
Are you done with your call, Araragi?
そしてその表情 あなたの奴隷(どれい)に
何か御用と見受けるぞ
I can see from your expression that you want something from your slave.
僕に奴隷はいない
I have no slave.
では私の意見は必要ないか
Then my opinion is not required.
心強いなあ
How reassuring.
いや 必要
No, it is.
必要だ
It is required.
神原 何か意見があるなら出してくれ
Kanbaru, if you have an idea, please.
よし わかった
Okay, got it.
こっちだぞ
This way.
公園の場所は知らないが
それが戦場ヶ原先輩の昔の家があったあたりというのであれば
I don't know where the park is, but if it's near where Senjougahara used to live,
then I can smell out the rough direction.
嗅覚で大体の方角はわかる
Let's go!
行くぞ
視覚じゃなくて嗅覚なのかよ
By smell? Not sight?
Come on, Araragi.
ほら 阿良々木先輩
Are you a
ninja or something?
阿良々木先輩 その迷い牛という怪異は
人を道に迷わす怪異なのだろう?
Araragi, the Lost Cow makes people lose track.
だったら 道を歩かなければいいじゃないか
All we have to do is avoid tracks.
僕達は午前三時頃 ついに
At around three in the morning, we finally reached
Namishiro Park
浪白公園に辿り着いたという次第である
Rouhaku Park.
あれ?
Huh?
いくらなんでも さっき電話をしてからわずか三時間だ
Barely three hours passed since our phone call.
それで焦れて帰ったりすまい
I can't imagine she got impatient and went home.
でも阿良々木先輩
Well, Araragi.
普通の人間は夜中に三時間も待たされたら帰るだろう
Normal human beings would go home after waiting for three hours at night.
そう言われればそうかもしれないけど
Well, I guess...
Oh.
そうだ
僕が道に迷わされていたように
Just as I was made to be lost on the way here,
待ち合わせをしていた臥煙さんもまた 何らかの怪異現象に襲われ
それでここにいないというケースは考えられないか?
Gaen perhaps had to face some kind of oddity while waiting and is no longer here.
Kanbaru. There's something I want.
神原 お願いがある
Go right ahead!
召し上がれ♪
No.
違う
無駄かもしれないけれど 手分けして
公園中を隈なく探してみたいんだ
It could be fruitless, but let's split up and search the park.
何かあったら声を上げてくれ
Call out if you find something.
Do you want me to scream?
悲鳴をあげればいいのか
悲鳴はあげないで
No screaming.
僕が捕まるから
I'd serve time.
了解 仕(つかまつ)った
Roger. I serve you.
Serve Time
Serve
Serve You
Araragi! Over here!
阿良々木先輩! いたぞ!
誰もいるようには見えないのだが
I can't see anyone.
いやいや 阿良々木先輩
Oh, please.
ほら よく見ろ
Take a closer look.
Shinobu!
し 忍!
おお お前様か
Oh, you.
遅かったのう
You took your sweet time.
That's so cute.
可愛いじゃねえか
おい 忍 どうしてお前がここに
Why are you here, Shinobu?
The monkey...
猿 か
ふん 手こずらせてくれたもんじゃ
It was a tough nut.
確かにこの子猫ちゃんは手を焼かせてくれたものだ
Yes, this little kitten was a handful.
Cat, huh?
猫のう
Let's ignore the pervert for now.
いや お前様
No, my master.
猿というのは この娘のことではない
I didn't mean her when I spoke of the monkey.
レインコートに長靴であったが こやつとは別人じゃ
It was wearing a raincoat and
rubber boots, but it wasn't her.
別人?
It wasn't her?
ともかく さっきまでどこぞのほうで
儂が戦っておった怪異じゃ
I'm speaking of the oddity I fought earlier.
猫と一緒にの
Together with the cat.
え? な... 何の話?
What are you talking about?
And a cat?
What cat?
What in the world is going on in this town right now?
色々と夢の競演じゃったの
It was all very dashing.
ま この程度 かすり傷じゃ
Well, these are all just scratches.
大過ないわい
Nothing bad.
お前様のほうは 大丈夫じゃったのか?
Have you been all right?
あ ああ お前と別れてから
えーっと あの"くらやみ"の件だけど
Yeah... As for the darkness...
No need.
否
その辺りはもう軽く聞いた
I got a rough rundown.
儂も色々 四百年以上 勘違いしておったようじゃの
It appears I was mistaken for four hundred years.
不細工な限りじゃわい
How foolish.
聞いたって 誰から聞いたのだ?
A rundown? From whom?
言うまでもなかろう
From whom do you think?
お前様を踏みつけた童女に聞いたのじゃ
I asked the little girl that stepped on your face.
僕を踏みつけた童女?
The little girl that stepped on my face?
はて なんのことやらさっぱり
What could you possibly be talking about?
僕を裸足で踏んだことがあるのは、
忍 お前だけだよ?
The only one who ever stepped on me barefoot is you.
儂は裸足でとは言うておらんぞ
I didn't say anything about being barefoot.
Oh, no!
はっ! しまった!
Is this what "the tongue ever turns to the aching tooth" means?
問うに落ちず語るに落ちるとはこのことか!
And you ache well and good, it seems.
落ちるところまで落ちたという感じじゃが
By the way, one can clearly see
marks of cute feet on your face.
ちゅーか 顔面に可愛らしい足跡がくっきり残っとるぞ
Oh, no!
なんと!
I've been wondering this whole time
what happened while I was unconscious.
私が意識を失っている間に何かあったのかなという疑問を
ずっと密かに心に秘めていた
言えよ!
Tell me!
気付いていたんなら!
Tell me if you saw it!
お前そんな先輩におんぶされて悦に入ってたのかよ!
Did you think it was funny being carried by someone like that?
まあ 本来ならばそんなマーキング
皮膚を剥(は)いでやりたいくらいに業腹(ごうはら)なんじゃが
Normally I would want to skin you out of spite for such a mark,
しかしあの人形娘には不本意にも救われてしもうたからの
but we were unwillingly saved by the doll.
このたびだけは広い心で勘弁してやるか
Let us overlook this matter.
救われてしもうた?
Saved?
おいおい 本当に何があったんだよ 忍
Honestly, what happened, Shinobu?
なに 言うほどのこともない
Nothing major.
儂と猫が猿に襲われとったとき
The cat and I were attacked by the monkey.
The doll appeared and, surprisingly, assisted us in our terrible battle.
苦戦しておったとき 突如現れたあの人形娘が
感心にも加勢に入ってくれたというだけのことじゃ
なんじゃったかの あの娘の必殺技
What was it called, her secret weapon?
"A rulebook of mostly exceptions"
アンリミテッド・ルールブック
Unlimited Rulebook...
とやらで 猿の右半身をぶっ飛ばしてくれた
She used that to blast away the right side of its body.
And you talked to her after that?
で 救われたのち 斧乃木ちゃんから
あれからの話を聞いたってことなのか
じゃあ
So...
そこで"くらやみ"の件やらを聞いたとして じゃあ
ならばその後の鎧武者の件も聞いたのだろうか?
That could be how she found out about the darkness, and probably also about the armor.
No, that's unlikely.
いや そういうわけではなさそうだ
ま お互い無事でよかったの
I'm just glad we're both unhurt.
否 無事 というわけではないのか
No, not unhurt.
儂とお前様のペアリングを
アロハ小僧の師匠とやらが回復させてくれるそうじゃの?
The link between us can apparently be restored by the master of the guy in the Hawaiian shirt.
じゃから合流すればよいと
人形娘は言っておったのじゃが
The doll told me to go meet you, but...
到着してみればお前様も
その師匠とやらもおらんではないか
When I got there, neither of you were here.
That's why...
じゃから
"じゃから"ブランコの下で寝てたって言うのか?
That's why you were sleeping under a swing?
どういう発想なんだよ
What kind of logic is that?
どういう発想の転換なんだよ
How do you reach that conclusion?
思わぬバトルで疲れていたとしても せめて寝るなら
もっと別の場所があるだろう
Okay, maybe you were tired from your battle, but at least choose somewhere else to sleep.
My master.
お前様
その話はあとでしょう
Let us talk about that later.
残念ながら まだ戦い終わってはいなかったようじゃ
Sadly, it appears my battle is not quite over.
まだ戦いは終わっていなかったようじゃ
I am not done fighting.
儂らの戦いは これからのようじゃの
Our battle has only just begun.
I hear your laughter near me
You were supposed to be there forever
I breathed onto the classroom window and wrote your name
only to panic and wipe it with my sleeve
I heard your voice from the hallway
and went home in hurry to hide my feelings
At some point I became unable
to talk to you normally
I can hear your laughter a ways away
You were supposed to be next to me forever
You knew how I felt
even when I said nothing
Now I know how important you were to me,
but we will never see each other again